Hello programmer, welcome back to this new tutorial today we will create the MySQL default
constancy.
So, in this MySQL is a handy feature for setting the default values for columns in the
table.
So, simply explain for what is the MySQL default constant and use to specify the default
value for a column and this value automatically inserted into the column for no value
explicit provided during and insert the operation.
So, in this session first of all, I can create the table with the default function.
So, just time saving for this process just follow and I can create simply the students
structure first on the ID, this the primary key and the name also for the start as a variable
and default for the active.
Okay, so this statement for here is insert provided during the insert operation and
here now just I can select all and execute then perfectly and you can see here this comment
for this operation successful and MySQL will return the confirmation this message okay.
So, just move on for the next example and here we can moving on it and existing column
to default okay.
So, first of all understand the table to define the table okay and it is called the students
okay.
Next step here I can create the outer so the columns for use the status okay and here
I can use the set for this is a default for in this instead I can create for the method
suppose like the inactive okay so here I can going to use the column okay so just create
simply a status for the set a default column and now here I'm going to create the semicolon
okay.
So, in this statement is created for the image script means no value is played by doing
here insert operation okay.
So, now just type perfectly run this statement and select all and now it is secure and
you can see here the statement is not directly defined okay.
So, here in this central just use the semicolon and now just again type and now this
is the same for this and just click on the default press this and just try and you can
see the same prompt for the inactive session okay.
So, here you can change for here it was the inactive okay.
So, here not different and here modify existing column and now just another word is defined
so here I can create for now inserting the data into a table for here default constant
okay.
So, now just remove and first of all here I can just tag this insert into for the storage
table and in this insert first of all I can declare for it okay it is nice to use for the
outer column and next step here I can use this is the name column okay.
And now just use this and this is the value and also here parenthesis first defined here
that is so on and also defined for the name is Zara or Lisa here it is completely create
and now start inserting the new student record in the student table only here I will
use the ID and the name column okay and provide this data to specify here the status column
and MySQL will use the default value in active for the operation okay.
So, now just select all and execute and now you can see perfectly completely affected
and here in this MySQL will return the confirmation message okay.
So, here it is completely done so now I can active for this statement so here I can create
so now just going to use the animal query and first of all here type the update for the
student stable and then going to the next step and here I will use you can use for the
set then the status okay and this is equal to create for here the in active message
and here for this query to the word so plus for ID is equal to 1 okay.
So, here this is completely used and now just I can select and see queue and you can
see see the result perfectly okay.
So, you can see here completely show for the message for on note this perfectly predicted
and here in the students for the status for the perfectly inactive okay.
So, now I can verify for the student table so first of all here I can type this the select
then start from the students okay so this is student stable and now here completely
you can I can select and now execute and you can see here this will perfectly show the message
so here I can create for the update for the startup and I can see ready to create the
inactive message okay.
So, here this is completely used for the default overview or the default constant in
the MySQL and here I can use for some practical example okay.
So, I hope you will have to understand the session so thank you for watching and happy
programming okay.